Eugene Gluhotorenko

Senior Software Engineer, Technical Lead

Minsk. Belarus



PROFILE

Solid software engineer with 9+ years of experience in delivering products. Expert in frontend development with backend background. Passionate about programming, software engineering, data visualization and especially about building rich web apps. My spare time I spend on reading popular science books, sport, traveling and developing open source.

SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, React, React Native, Swift, MobX, WebSocket, styled-components, Redux, PixiJS, HTML, CSS, Git and a lot of other libraries and tools.

EXPERIENCE

Software TechLead

CCDS / Nezaboodka | Oct 2019 → current

TypeScript React MobX Cornerstone.js DICOM Scrum / Agile

- Participating in development of a Medical Al Platform to help data scientists to train models on a huge amount of medical imaging data.
- Building web viewer for high-performance loading and visualization of medical data and ML model generated output.
- Developing web platform for processing medical studies.
- Taking responsibilities for frontend provisioning.

Senior Software Engineer

MintData | Aug 2016 → Mar 2018

TypeScript React MobX WebSocket MobX State Tree

- Building a visual programming platform for creating real-time applications based on spreadsheets and visual GUI builder.
- Technical interviewing of new candidates.

Lead Software Developer

Nexus / CTDEV | Oct 2013 → Aug 2016

JavaScript AngularJS Highchars D3.js Node.js Scrum / Agile

- Building fintech news portal based on recommendation engine.
- Implementing data visualization tools like charts, graphs, maps.

- Writing custom gulp/grunt plugins for complex build system.
- Helping the company to hire new engineers.

Senior Software Engineer

SoftSwiss | Apr 2018 → Oct 2019



- Developing game engine for multi-platform 2D games.
- Performance optimisation
- Writing server-side scripts for processing images and audio
- Technical interviewing of new candidates

Senior Software Developer

EPAM Systems | Dec 2010 → Sep 2013



- Develop a platform for publishing financial apps.
- HTML5 apps for the platform (Time series data charts, market/exchange data viewers and etc.).
- JavaScript API for third-party app developers.
- Develop back-end services.

BLOG ARTICLES

 How styled-components works: A deep dive under the hood Aug 2018

OPEN SOURCE

- <u>Babbler</u> A language switcher for macOS
- Subtitle Translator Chrome Extension for fast subtitles translation on Netflix.
- angular2-highcharts Highcharts for your Angular project.

EDUCATION

Belarusian University of Informatics and Radioelectronics

B.Sc | Computer Science, Network systems